Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got an upper intermediate level lesson.
我是Catherine，今天我们带来了一节中高级课程。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to go and buy shoes.
我们要去买鞋。
Okay, this is very fun.
好的，这很有趣。
I like buying shoes.
我喜欢买鞋。
Although I have a hard time finding shoes in my size sometimes but we're here talking
虽然有时候很难找到适合我尺码的鞋，但我们今天要聊的是
about men's shoes specifically.
男士鞋，具体来说。
That's right.
没错。
We've actually decided to talk about this topic, buying shoes separately between men
我们决定把这个话题分开讨论，分别讲男士和女士买鞋，
and women's shoes because I think each type of shoe has its own type of vocab and that
因为我觉得每种鞋都有自己的一套词汇，
can be very useful for men or women.
这对男士或女士都很有用。
That's right.
没错。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk more
那么，我们来听一下今天的对话，稍后我们会回来
about the specifics of men's shoe styles.
详细聊聊男士鞋款的具体内容。
Hi, I'm looking for a pair of shoes for my son.
你好，我想给我儿子买双鞋。
Sure thing.
没问题。
Here we are.
这边请。
If you're looking for dress shoes, we have several different styles of Oxford for boys.
如果您在找正装鞋，我们有好几款不同的牛津鞋适合男孩。
We also carry athletic shoes, hiking boots.
我们还有运动鞋和登山靴。
Oh, Jacob, how about these sneakers?
哦，雅各布，这双运动鞋怎么样？
Mom, they've got Velcro.
妈妈，它们有魔术贴。
Well, then how about these?
嗯，那这双呢？
What is this style called?
这种款式叫什么？
They're tennis shoes.
它们是网球鞋。
They're very popular with teens and young adults.
在青少年和年轻人中很流行。
Oh, mom, can I get these?
哦，妈妈，我能买这双吗？
What are those?
那些是什么？
They're Chuck Taylors.
它们是查克·泰勒鞋。
Everyone has them.
大家都有。
Can I please?
求你了，可以吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Would they go with your clothes?
它们和你的衣服搭吗？
The backs are really high and the way the tongue just sticks up, they're almost like
鞋帮很高，鞋舌翘起来的样子，几乎像
a boot and the sole doesn't look like it would have a very good grip.
靴子一样，而且鞋底看起来抓地力不太好。
They're only $45 and they've got cool fluorescent orange shoelaces.
只要45美元，还有酷炫的荧光橙色鞋带。
Mom!
妈妈！
Okay, try them on.
好吧，试试吧。
What size are your feet?
你穿多大码的鞋？
He's a size nine.
他穿九码。
We'll try a size 43 on you first and see how that fits.
我们先给你试一双43码的，看看合不合适。
A what?
什么？
They come in European sizes.
这些是欧码的。
He should be a size 43.
他应该穿43码。
I'll be right back.
我马上回来。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So as you saw, we have a lot of different shoe styles and so we're going to take a
就像你看到的，我们有很多不同的鞋款，所以我们要在
look at these on Language Takeaway.
“语言小课堂”里仔细看看这些。
Language Takeaway.
语言小课堂。
Okay, first up we have a very popular style of shoe.
好的，首先我们有一种非常流行的鞋款。
This is called an athletic shoe.
这叫运动鞋。
Okay, athletic shoe.
好的，运动鞋。
Now I imagine that athletes wear these shoes.
我猜运动员会穿这种鞋。
Good guess, Marco.
猜得好，马可。
So athletic athletes.
所以是运动员穿的运动鞋。
This is actually for sports in general.
这其实泛指运动用的鞋。
So this is sports shoes but in English we say athletic shoes.
所以这是运动鞋，但在英语里我们说 athletic shoes。
Okay, so it's not specifically for any type of sport but they're just comfortable shoes
好的，所以它不是专门针对某种运动，只是舒适的鞋子。
that you can do most sports in.
你可以穿着进行大多数运动。
Right, like running shoes and basketball shoes and soccer shoes.
对，比如跑步鞋、篮球鞋和足球鞋。
These are all kinds of athletic shoes.
这些都是运动鞋的一种。
Very good.
很好。
Okay.
好的。
So these types of athletic shoes, they're usually kind of low, right?
所以这类运动鞋通常比较低，对吧？
They don't have a lot of support around the ankle.
它们对脚踝的支撑不多。
No, but they do have a lot of support in the heel, the bottom of your foot.
不，但它们在脚跟和脚底确实有很多支撑。
Right, because you're running, you need that extra support.
对，因为你在跑步，需要额外的支撑。
Exactly.
没错。
Now on the opposite, if you're going hiking, if you're maybe trekking, then you need a
相反，如果你要去远足或徒步旅行，那么你需要一种
special type of shoe that's going to give more ankle support and these are called hiking
特殊的鞋子，能提供更多脚踝支撑，这些被称为远足
boots.
靴。
Okay, hiking boots.
好的，远足靴。
So like you were saying, you get a lot of support in your ankle, that's the back of
就像你说的，脚踝得到很多支撑，那是脚的后部
your foot and the area around your leg.
和腿周围的区域。
So these shoes tend to come higher on your leg.
所以这些鞋子通常会在腿上更高一些。
They're taller on your leg and they're usually pretty heavy.
它们在腿上更高，而且通常很重。
And I think they are more weather resistant.
而且我觉得它们更耐天气。
So if it rains or if it's wet, these shoes will respond better.
所以如果下雨或潮湿，这些鞋子会表现更好。
You're not going to get wet feet.
你的脚不会湿的。
So hiking boots.
所以是登山靴。
And now we have another interesting word, I never really understood why they're called
现在我们又有一个有趣的词，我一直不太明白为什么它们被叫做
this way, but we have sneakers.
这样，但我们有“sneakers”。
Sneakers.
“Sneakers”。
Okay, I love sneakers.
好吧，我喜欢运动鞋。
I always wear sneakers.
我总是穿运动鞋。
A very common brand that you see with sneakers is Puma, also Adidas.
一个很常见的运动鞋品牌是彪马，还有阿迪达斯。
So Converse is another brand.
所以匡威是另一个品牌。
Sneakers are shoes that are not fancy, they're not like leather or work shoes, but they're
运动鞋是不花哨的鞋子，它们不像皮鞋或工作鞋，但
also not athletic shoes because you don't necessarily use them when you're playing sports.
也不是运动鞋，因为你运动时不一定会穿它们。
They're basically very simple shoes for normal daily stuff.
它们基本上是用于日常活动的非常简单的鞋子。
Normal walking.
正常走路。
Young people wear them usually.
通常年轻人穿它们。
Okay, sneakers.
好吧，运动鞋。
Now I never understood why they're called sneakers because I think if you sneak maybe
我一直不明白为什么它们叫“sneakers”，因为我觉得如果你偷偷接近
on someone, I guess these shoes are good for sneaking up on people.
别人，也许这些鞋子很适合悄悄靠近别人。
Perhaps, I don't know.
也许吧，我不知道。
They're less noisy than other shoes.
它们比其他鞋子噪音小。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
Okay, so we have sneakers.
好吧，所以我们有运动鞋。
And now another type of shoe that can be a little bit confusing, they're called tennis
现在另一种可能有点让人困惑的鞋子，它们被称为网球
shoes.
鞋。
Okay, tennis shoes can be considered a kind of sneaker.
好吧，网球鞋可以被视为一种运动鞋。
Again, it's not the kind of shoe that you would normally wear to work.
同样，这不是你通常上班穿的鞋子。
It's not leather, it's not a hiking boot.
它不是皮革的，也不是登山靴。
They're low shoes, so low ankles generally.
它们是低帮鞋，所以通常脚踝处很低。
And they tie up.
而且它们系带。
But you would think that you use these shoes to play tennis.
但你会以为这些鞋子是用来打网球的。
Not necessarily.
不一定。
But not necessarily, right?
但不一定，对吧？
I mean, you don't have to play tennis.
我的意思是，你不一定要打网球。
They're not specifically designed to play tennis.
它们不是专门为打网球设计的。
Perhaps originally they were tennis shoes for the game tennis, but nowadays they're
也许最初它们是为网球运动设计的网球鞋，但现在它们
very, very common.
非常非常普遍。
They're like sneakers.
它们就像运动鞋。
They're shoes that most young people wear to school or to play around in.
它们是大多数年轻人上学或玩耍时穿的鞋子。
Okay, so they're kind of like you say, a sneaker.
好吧，所以它们就像你说的，是一种运动鞋。
And now moving on, these might seem a little bit strange, but we call them Chuck Taylors.
现在继续，这些可能看起来有点奇怪，但我们称它们为“Chuck Taylors”。
Chuck Taylors, well basically Chuck Taylor is a brand.
“Chuck Taylors”，基本上Chuck Taylor是一个品牌。
Converse Chuck Taylors.
匡威Chuck Taylors。
We also call them Chucks.
我们也叫它们“Chucks”。
And this is a style of shoe that this brand made very famous.
这是一种这个品牌非常出名的鞋子款式。
They're very, very thin canvas shoes.
它们是非常非常薄的帆布鞋。
So the fabric is not leather, it's canvas.
所以面料不是皮革，是帆布。
And they come in bright red or black or green.
它们有亮红色、黑色或绿色。
And some of them are very low.
有些非常低帮。
And some of them have a piece of the ankle that comes up.
有些有包裹脚踝的部分。
So it almost looks like a boot to a certain extent.
所以它看起来在某种程度上几乎像靴子。
But it's not like a hiking boot.
但它不像登山靴。
It's not very hard.
它不是很硬。
It doesn't support your ankle as much.
它不太支撑脚踝。
It's just the style is higher.
只是款式更高。
Exactly.
没错。
And so because these are made of fabric, they're very thin.
而且因为这些是布料做的，它们很薄。
They're very light.
它们很轻。
They're not very good for hiking, for example.
它们不太适合徒步旅行，比如。
Right.
对。
So these are called Chuck Taylors.
所以这些被称为“Chuck Taylors”。
They're very, very popular with teenagers, right?
它们在青少年中非常非常流行，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Teenagers all over the world wear Chuck Taylors.
全世界的青少年都穿Chuck Taylors。
And I think they're very old.
而且我觉得它们很古老。
This style, these Chuck Taylors have been around for like 30 years.
这种款式，这些Chuck Taylors已经存在了大约30年。
Yeah, I think since the 1960s or 70s.
是的，我觉得从20世纪60年代或70年代开始。
But they're still popular.
但它们仍然很流行。
Yeah.
是的。
And they haven't changed.
而且它们没有改变过。
They haven't changed.
它们没有改变过。
Right.
对。
So these are the five types or styles of shoes that we're going to take a look at.
所以这就是我们要看的五种类型或款式的鞋子。
Why don't we move on now to more specific vocab related to the parts of the shoe on
我们为什么不继续到语言摘录第二部分，看看与鞋子部位相关的更具体词汇呢？
Language Takeaway Part 2.
语言摘录。
Language Takeaway.
Okay.
好吧。
So Jacob is talking to his mother and his mom wants to know, hey, how about these sneakers?
所以雅各布正在和他妈妈说话，他妈妈想知道，嘿，这些运动鞋怎么样？
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
And Jacob says, Mom, they've got Velcro.
雅各布说，妈妈，它们有魔术贴。
Okay.
好吧。
So Marco, what's this Velcro Jacob speaks of?
那么马可，雅各布说的这个魔术贴是什么？
Well, as you can see, Velcro is capitalized, right?
嗯，如你所见，Velcro 是大写的，对吧？
And so that means this is a proper noun and it's actually a brand.
所以这意味着它是一个专有名词，实际上是一个品牌。
Okay.
好的。
It's like Chuck Taylors.
就像 Chuck Taylors 一样。
Like Chuck Taylors.
就像 Chuck Taylors。
So Velcro is supposed kind of like a zipper, right?
所以 Velcro 有点像拉链，对吧？
A fastener.
一种扣件。
But instead of zipping it up, you just put two pieces of cloth together and they stick.
但不用拉上拉链，你只需把两块布放在一起，它们就会粘住。
Okay.
好的。
And when you pull them apart, they make that sound.
当你把它们拉开时，它们会发出那种声音。
They make a loud sound.
它们会发出很大的声音。
And so sometimes with baby shoes or young children's shoes, we don't want to tie them
所以有时候在婴儿鞋或幼儿鞋上，我们不想系鞋带，
because that's too hard.
因为那太难了。
So we have Velcro.
所以我们用 Velcro。
This is a kind of fabric, like you said, that sticks together.
这是一种布料，就像你说的，能粘在一起。
We don't have to spend all this time tying things.
我们不用花那么多时间系东西。
So you see Velcro on hats, on gloves, on jackets, on shoes.
所以你在帽子、手套、夹克、鞋子上都能看到 Velcro。
It's a very popular way to make things, close things or to keep things secure.
这是一种很流行的方法，用来制作、闭合或固定东西。
In a very easy way, right?
用很简单的方式，对吧？
You just push them together and that's it.
你只需把它们压在一起就行了。
They're sealed.
它们就封好了。
Exactly.
没错。
So the next time you see it, now you know that it's called Velcro.
所以下次你看到它时，你就知道它叫 Velcro 了。
I imagine in other languages, it's probably called the same thing.
我想在其他语言里，它可能也叫同样的名字。
Well, right.
嗯，对。
It's the brand name.
这是品牌名。
Yeah.
是的。
So, okay.
所以，好吧。
And well, now moving on to the parts of the shoe, we have the tongue.
嗯，现在继续讲鞋子的部分，我们有鞋舌。
Okay.
好的。
Well, think about the body part, the tongue, right?
嗯，想想身体部位，舌头，对吧？
When you look at your tongue, it's straight and it's flat and it kind of curves at the
当你看着你的舌头时，它是直的、扁平的，而且底部有点弯曲。
bottom.
底部。
Right.
对。
So when you're putting your shoe on, you know, in the front of the shoe, you can make it
所以当你穿鞋时，你知道，在鞋子前面，你可能会让它卡住。
stuck.
卡住。
You have to pull the tongue.
你得拉一下鞋舌。
Right.
对。
It's a piece of fabric or piece of the shoe where the top of your foot is.
它是一块布料或鞋子的一部分，位于你的脚背上方。
Yeah.
是的。
Very good.
很好。
So that's called the tongue.
所以那叫鞋舌。
Now, some shoes have a very small tongue or a low one and others have a very high one.
现在，有些鞋子有很小的鞋舌或低鞋舌，而其他的则有很高的鞋舌。
Like for example, Chuck Taylors, they have a big tongue.
比如 Chuck Taylors，它们就有大鞋舌。
That's right.
没错。
Very long tongue.
很长的鞋舌。
And so the tongue is the part that rests on top of your foot.
所以鞋舌是放在你脚背上的部分。
And usually the shoelaces are over the tongue.
通常鞋带在鞋舌上面。
Exactly.
没错。
And now moving on to the bottom part of the shoe, that's called the sole.
现在继续讲鞋子的底部，那叫鞋底。
Okay.
好的。
S-O-L-E.
S-O-L-E。
Sole.
鞋底。
This is a really important part of shoes.
这是鞋子非常重要的一部分。
I always look at the sole before I buy a pair of shoes because this is the part that you
我买鞋前总是看鞋底，因为这是你用得最多的部分，因为你在地上走路。
use the most because you're walking on the ground.
走路。
Right.
对。
So for example, hiking boots, they will have a very high sole and they will have kind of
比如，登山靴会有很高的鞋底，而且会有某种花纹，这样你在泥地上走就不会滑倒，对吧？
like a pattern so that you don't slip if you're walking on dirt, right?
泥地。
That's right.
没错。
Sometimes rubber, a rubber sole.
有时是橡胶，橡胶鞋底。
But other times, like Chuck Taylors also have a rubber sole but it's very thin.
但其他时候，比如 Chuck Taylors 也有橡胶鞋底，但很薄。
It's very thin.
很薄。
And some shoes, for example, they have a plastic sole maybe because they're used for other
有些鞋子，比如，可能有塑料鞋底，也许因为它们用于其他用途，所以在光滑表面上可能会有点滑。
purposes so they might be a little bit slippery if you go onto a smooth surface.
光滑表面。
Exactly.
没错。
So the sole, that's the bottom part of the shoe.
所以鞋底，就是鞋子的底部。
And the last part of the shoe that we're going to take a look at and probably the most
我们要看的最后一个部分，可能也是最重要的，是鞋带。
important are the shoelaces.
鞋带。
Shoelaces.
So shoelaces are basically long pieces of string that you use to tie your shoes closed
所以鞋带基本上是你用来系紧鞋子的长绳子，因为你希望鞋子在脚上紧一些。
because you want your shoes to be tight on your foot.
紧一些。
You don't want it to be too loose otherwise it might fall off.
你不希望它太松，否则可能会掉下来。
And Chuck Taylors and some other shoes are very famous for having crazy colored laces
而 Chuck Taylors 和其他一些鞋子以有疯狂颜色的鞋带而闻名，或者人们用疯狂颜色的鞋带来系它们。
or for people using crazy colored laces to tie them up.
系它们。
Right.
对。
So that's the part they use to tie or tighten the shoe with.
所以那是用来系或收紧鞋子的部分。
So on the opposite, if a shoe doesn't have shoelaces, it's probably going to have Velcro.
所以反过来，如果一双鞋没有鞋带，它很可能会有 Velcro。
That's right.
没错。
Velcro or shoelaces.
魔术贴还是鞋带。
Okay.
好的。
So those are all the words that we have for you today.
以上就是我们今天为你准备的所有单词。
Why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue for the last time.
我们不如回去再听一遍对话吧。
Hi.
嗨。
I'm looking for a pair of shoes for my son.
我在给我儿子找一双鞋。
Sure thing.
没问题。
Here we are.
我们到了。
If you're looking for dress shoes, we have several different styles of Oxford for boys.
如果你在找正装鞋，我们有几种不同的男孩牛津鞋款式。
We also carry athletic shoes, hiking boots.
我们还有运动鞋、登山靴。
Oh, Jacob, how about these sneakers?
哦，雅各布，这双运动鞋怎么样？
Mom, they've got Velcro.
妈，它们有魔术贴。
Well, then how about these?
嗯，那这双呢？
What is this style called?
这种款式叫什么？
They're tennis shoes.
它们是网球鞋。
They're very popular with teens and young adults.
它们在青少年和年轻人中很受欢迎。
Oh, mom, can I get these?
哦，妈，我能买这双吗？
What are those?
那些是什么？
They're Chuck Taylors.
它们是查克·泰勒鞋。
Everyone has them.
每个人都有。
Can I please?
求你了行吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Would they go with your clothes?
它们跟你的衣服搭吗？
The backs are really high and the way the tongue just sticks up, they're almost like
鞋跟很高，鞋舌翘起来的样子，几乎像
a boot.
靴子。
And the sole doesn't look like it would have a very good grip.
而且鞋底看起来抓地力不太好。
They're only $45.
只要45美元。
And they've got cool, fluorescent orange shoelaces.
而且它们有酷炫的荧光橙色鞋带。
Mom!
妈！
Okay, try them on.
好吧，试试吧。
What size are your feet?
你穿多大码？
He's a size nine.
他是九码。
We'll try a size 43 on you first and see how that fits.
我们先给你试穿43码，看看合不合适。
A what?
什么？
They come in European sizes.
它们用的是欧洲尺码。
He should be a size 43.
他应该穿43码。
I'll be right back.
我马上回来。
All right, so talking about shoes, you say that you always take a look at the sole.
好的，说到鞋子，你说你总是会看鞋底。
Why is this?
为什么？
Because I'm always afraid that my shoes are going to wear out.
因为我总是担心我的鞋会磨坏。
And I don't buy shoes very often.
而且我不常买鞋。
I love sneakers.
我喜欢运动鞋。
I love my Pumas.
我喜欢我的彪马鞋。
And I love flat shoes.
而且我喜欢平底鞋。
And so when you buy a pair of shoes you really like, you don't want to buy another pair in
所以当你买到一双非常喜欢的鞋时，你不想
six months.
六个月后又买一双。
You want to get a pair that has a really good sole so that it will last for a long time.
你想买一双鞋底很好的鞋，这样能穿很久。
Right, right.
对，对。
Yeah, that's true.
是啊，没错。
I think for me, yeah, that's probably one of the most important parts is the sole, as
我觉得对我来说，嗯，那可能是最重要的部分之一，就是鞋底，只要
long as it's comfortable.
它舒服就行。
Because some soles of some shoes can be very rigid.
因为有些鞋的鞋底可能很硬。
Yeah.
是啊。
So it's a little bit uncomfortable to walk with.
所以走起路来有点不舒服。
But I don't know.
但我不知道。
I don't really have that many pairs of shoes if I think about it.
我想想，我其实没有那么多双鞋。
Well, most people have one fancy pair of shoes for special occasions.
嗯，大多数人会有一双好鞋用于特殊场合。
And then a pair of work shoes that are leather.
然后一双皮质的上班鞋。
And then maybe a couple pairs of sneakers and some sandals for the summer.
然后可能几双运动鞋和几双凉鞋过夏天。
So you have sandals and you have flip flops.
所以你有凉鞋和人字拖。
Are they the same?
它们一样吗？
Well, sandals is basically a kind of shoe.
嗯，凉鞋基本上是一种鞋类。
It's an open shoe that you wear in the summer.
它是一种夏天穿的露趾鞋。
Flip flops are a kind of sandal.
人字拖是凉鞋的一种。
So they usually have a V in the front.
所以它们前面通常有个V形。
And that's where you put your big toe.
那是放大脚趾的地方。
The second toe.
第二个脚趾。
So we wear them in the shower or at the beach.
所以我们洗澡或去海滩时穿它们。
They're usually made of plastic or rubber so that you can get them wet.
它们通常由塑料或橡胶制成，这样能弄湿。
But flip flops are a kind of sandal.
但人字拖是凉鞋的一种。
Very good.
非常好。
It's very interesting how many styles and types of shoes.
鞋子的款式和种类真有趣。
And actually for men, I think it's not that complicated.
实际上对男人来说，我觉得没那么复杂。
But when we get into women's shoes, then we'll see a lot of different things.
但当我们谈到女鞋时，就会看到很多不同的东西。
There are too many styles.
款式太多了。
I can't keep track.
我记不过来。
All right.
好了。
So that's all the time we have for today.
这就是我们今天的所有时间。
But we'll see you guys on the website if you have any questions, any doubts, or if you
但如果你有任何问题、任何疑惑，或者如果你
just want to chat with us.
只是想和我们聊聊天。
We'll see you at EnglishPod.com.
我们会在EnglishPod.com等你。
See you guys there.
各位，那里见。
All right.
好的。
Try it out.
试试看吧。